- [Instructor] Okay, so let's start adding some meat
to our application and build the components,
and add them to our main app.
We'll also add a class component to our main app
where we'll manage the state.
Okay, so the first thing I'm going to do
in all these components here, I am going to add some meat,
so we have something that we can load,
and check that our application actually is working.
So I'm going to create on the first one, what I need.
I'm going to create a functional component
in this one PlayerForm
return.
And I'm going to do a simple div Player Form.
So this is the Player Form,
and I'm going to export default PlayerForm.
Awesome.
So we have now our first,
and actually you don't need to import React,
I just wanted to import it just to show you
that in some cases people like to do that,
but you don't necessarily need it,
because it's a functional component.
So basically functional components are functions,
so you don't need to have React loaded.
Okay, so I'm going to do that,
and I'm going to repeat right here.
I'm just going to change this to
PlayerList,
Player List,
save.
I'm going to do the same here.
And this is going to be PlayerSingle,
Player Single.
And we're good to go for these.
So we have our three components that have something
that we can load and see on the screen once
we update all this.
And then in the main app,
I'm going to start changing a few things.
So in this one, I'm going to need to import React,
because I'm going to use a class component,
and that's really important in order for me
to use the class component.
I'm going to also import the three components
that I just created, so PlayerForm
from
Player,
PlayerForm,
and I'm going to copy this,
paste this,
PlayerList.
And then
Player
Single.
And there's a typo here.
And again, these are the type of errors
that breaks an application, FYI.
And if you want to make sure, you can go,
and take a look at how you exported these.
So you can check PlayerForm, PlayerList,
PlayerSingle, this is how you exported them,
and you should be good to go.
Now, this is where I'm going to change the whole thing.
So I'm going to basically delete all this,
and call this a class
App
extends
React.Component
like this.
And it renders,
and then return
the component that I'm going to start typing.
Okay, so now, what we're going to do is start
using materialized CSS here.
So the first thing I'm going to do is create a div.
And inside that div I'm going to use
a class,
container-fluid.
Inside of that div,
I'm going to start using another div
with a className row.
Inside of that div, I'm going to have the menu.
For now it's going to be called menu.
We're going to change that as we work on the application.
And there's going to be a few classes used for that.
So s12
Menu.
And now, make sure you get out of that row here.
And we're going to use another div
of className row.
And inside of that one we're going to have the Player List.
So
className
col s3.
So basically what we're doing here,
we're separating each of these elements,
and we're going to have the PlayerList here.
And I'm going to explain as I finish this,
I'm just going to finish the code,
and then explain what I'm doing here,
and how I'm actually separating these
in my CSS.
And then I'm going to add the PlayerSingle.
Again, we're going to change some of this
as we build the application,
but for now, I just want to add these components,
so as I work on them, you can see them,
and render them in the application.
So we're not waiting too long
before we can actually see what we're doing.
Going to do another row, again,
you want to get out of that div here.
So this is a row which includes the PlayerList,
and PlayerSingle.
And then I'm going to add a last row that is going
to have the PlayerForm.
Okay,
now, let me explain the CSS that's happening here.
So here I'm going to have the PlayerForm.
Okay, so I have all my components added to my class here.
And what I've done is I create a big container
that is going to be fluid.
So basically resize with the different sizes
of your application.
Then I have a row which basically expands to the full row
with a menu, which is going to be on that row.
So I'm going to have a menu.
And then the second row, what I'm going to have is
in between this row and this row,
I'm going to have a PlayerList and PlayerSingle,
which will split the screen in between three,
which will have PlayerList,
and then nine, which will have a PlayerSingle.
So if you want to understand what's happening here,
every row has 12 columns,
and every
element here in my row will take three for this one,
and nine for this one.
And this will basically take full row,
and the menu will take full row.
So in theory, the menu should be full screen,
and then in that row, we're going to have PlayerList
that will take three columns,
and then a PlayerSingle is going to take nine columns.
And then in the last row, I'm going to have the PlayerForm,
which will take the full width of that row.
So if I save this, now, as you can see, there's no error.
So we're all good.
And if we go into our application,
and we basically refresh, you have the menu here,
you have the Player List, Player Single,
and then Player Form.
And as we add elements to all this,
it's going to basically resize accordingly.
So as we add CSS,
and specific things inside of these,
we're going to basically see this properly.
All right, so now we've added some meat to our application.
Let's move on.